John P. Clum papers, 1860-1970 (bulk, 1874-1932)
Clum, (John P.)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
John P. Clum papers, 1860-1970 (bulk, 1874-1932)
AZ 003
Clum, John P., 1851-1932
Collection consists of the papers of John P. Clum and family. Correspondence, diaries, scrapbooks, photographs, typescripts, newspaper and magazine articles are by or about John P. Clum; a smaller quantity of typescripts, reprints, and biographical items concern John's son Woodworth Clum. Much of the material consists of writings by the Clums and others about the Apache Indians, Geronimo's capture, and events in Tombstone, Arizona.
3 linear feet
Univeristy of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
John P. Clum was an Indian agent at the San Carlos Indian Reservation in southeast Arizona from 1874 to 1877. He later served as founder and editor of the Tombstone Epitaph newspaper, postmaster, and mayor of Tombstone, Arizona, as well as postal inspector and lecturer in Alaska. His son, Woodworth Clum, was an editor of the Washington Star newspaper, and the author of a book about his father entitled Apache Agent.
Organization
This collection is organized into 10 series:
I. Correspondence
II. Diaries
III. Manuscripts
IV. Publications
V. Clippings
VI. Scrapbooks
VII. Legal documents
VIII. Miscellaneous materials
IX. Materials concerning Woodward Clum
X. Photographs
Scope and Content Note
Collection consists of the papers of John P. Clum and family. Correspondence, diaries, scrapbooks, photographs, typescripts, newspaper and magazine articles are by or about John P. Clum; a smaller quantity of typescripts, reprints, and biographical items concern John's son Woodworth Clum. Much of the material consists of writings by the Clums and others about the Apache Indians, Geronimo's capture, and events in Tombstone, Arizona. The bulk of the correspondence is between John and his wife Mary Clum, from 1876 to 1880. These letters, a diary from 1875, and some official documents contain information on his tenure as an Indian agent in Arizona.
Photographs, some original but mostly reprints, depict John, Mary, Woodworth, other Clum family members, and friends including Wyatt Earp. Identified Apache individuals are represented in formal portraits taken in Washington, D.C., where Clum took them in 1876. Group photos of Apaches show them on the San Carlos Reservation and other locations, both before and after Geronimo's capture. An 1898 diary, 1898 Alaskan newspapers, scrapbooks, and photographs chronicle Clum's time in Alaska. Miscellaneous items include an 1860 history book, and an account of Clum family history.
Related Material
Additional materials concerning John Clum are located in the John P. Clum Collection (MS 284).
Access Terms
Clum, John P., 1851-1932 -- Archives
Clum, Woodworth
Geronimo, 1829-1909
Clum family -- Genealogy
Frontier and pioneer life -- Arizona -- Cochise County
Apache Indians -- Government relations -- History
Apache Indians -- Photographs
San Carlos Indian Reservation (Ariz.) -- History
Tombstone (Ariz.) -- History
Alaska -- Description and travel -- History -- 19th century
Correspondence
Diaries
Photographs
Tintypes
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Edw. P. Smith, Office of Indian Affairs, to John Clum. February 27, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Wedding invitation for wedding of Mary D. Ware to John P. Clum. Sent to S.B. Chapin from Mrs. T.C. Ware. 1876 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - J.Q. Smith, Office of Indian Affairs, to John Clum. March 20, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum's mother. November 25, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - (No first name) Smith, War Dept., telegram to John Clum. March 20, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. April 13, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum. April 16, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. April 20, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Clum to Major J.F. Wade, 9th Calvary. April 22, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. April 25, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum. April 25, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum. April 27, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum. May 22, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mary Clum to (her cousin) G.N. Strong. February 13, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Clum to (his grandmother) Jane Clum. October 22, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum (letter is incomplete). May 19, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. May 20, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. May 23, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. May 27, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. May 31, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. June 5, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. June 8, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum (letter is incomplete). June 8, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. June 9, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. June 18, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum. June 18, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. June 22, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. June 24, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. June 26, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. June 27, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. June 30, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. July 1, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. No Date (circa. July, 1879) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum (letter is incomplete). No Date (circa. July, 1879) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum (letter is incomplete). No Date (circa. July, 1879) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. July 2, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. July 4, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. July 5, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. July 6, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. July 7, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. July 12, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum (enclosed with the letter are letters to Mary from John's mother and sister). July 13, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum (letter is incomplete). July 14, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. July 16, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum. July 16, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. July 17, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum. July 17, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum. July 20, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. July 14, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum (letter is incomplete). No Date (circa. August, 1879) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum (letter is incomplete). No Date (circa. August, 1879) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - John Clum to Mary Clum. August 30, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. September 14, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. September 15, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. September 16, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. September 19, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum (letter is incomplete). No Date (circa. May, 1880) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. May 22, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum. May 27, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum (letter is incomplete). June 4, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Clum to John Clum's mother. December 5, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - John Clum to his mother. December 20, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - John Clum to Woodworth Clum. June 12, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Woodworth Clum to John Clum (letter is incomplete). May 26, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - John Clum to Col. W.N. Monroe. May 18, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - John Clum to Walter H. Cole, editor of the Tombstone Epitaph. May 1, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series II: Dairies
  - John Clum diary. Written in Arizona and on a trip to Washington, D.C. March 1, 1875-December 23, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - John Clum diary. Written in Alaska. March 5, 1898-September 7, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series III: Manuscripts
  - Autobiography by John Clum, chapters 15-22. Some portions used by Woodworth Clum in his biography of John Clum, entitled Apache Agent. No Date (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Lo, the Poor Indian Agent" by John Clum. No Date (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "On the Trail" by John Clum. October, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fragments of autobiographical manuscripts by John Clum. 1898-1909 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Publications
  - The Third Book of History by Peter Parley (Boston: Swan, Brewer and Tileston, 1860). Signed: John P. Clum, Santa Fe, N.M. 1860 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sunset Magazine. Includes an article by John Clum entitled "Fighting Geronimo: A Story of the Apache Indian Campaign of 1876." May, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Geronimo" by John Clum. Extract from the New Mexico Historical Review. January, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Victorio, Head Chief of the Warm Springs Apaches in 1877, at Ojo Caliente, New Mexico" by John Clum. Reprint from the New Mexico Historical Review. 1929 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "The San Carlos Apache Police, Parts I and II" by John Clum. Reprints from the New Mexico Historical Review. 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "It All Happened in Tombstone" by John Clum. One extracted version and one page proof version from the Arizona Historical Review. October, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Truth about the Apaches Told in the Annual Reports by John P. Clum, United States Indian Agent for the Apache Indians at San Carlos, Arizona. Submitted to the Commissioner of Indian Affairs for 1874, 1875, 1876, 1877 by John Clum (Los Angeles: Adcraft, 1931). One full version and one partial version. 1931 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Nellie Cashman" by John Clum. Extract from the Arizona Historical Review. January, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "John P. Clum" by Leslie E. Gregory. Extract from the Arizona Historical Review. July, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series V: Clippings
  - Handwritten transcripts of clippings from the Arizona Citizen. Most concern John Clum and Apaches. 1875-1877 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, primarily from the Tombstone Epitaph. Most concern John Clum and family. Includes clippings on Mary Clum's death (1880) and an assassination attempt on John Clum (1881). Note: Oversize materials from this file are located in Box #6. 1880-1881 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Clippings from various newspapers and publications. Most concern John Clum and family. 1880-1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Clippings concerning the death of John Clum. Includes a typescript of remarks made by Raymond C. Brooks at Clum's funeral. 1932 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Series VI: Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook. Most of the materials concern John Clum. 1868-1930 (Box 3A-3B)
  - Scrapbook. Most of the materials concern John Clum. 1890-1913 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Series VII: Legal Documents
  - Lease of Gilded Age Mining Claim, Tombstone, by John Clum from the Gilded Age Mining Co. June 24, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Quit-claim deed for property in Tombstone from James Clark, John Rouse, and John Anderson to John Clum. April 22, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Series VIII: Miscellaneous Materials
  - Booklet entitled: Claverack (John Clum was born in Claverack, New York). 1892 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photocopies of three letters from Harold D. Clum to Cornelius W. Clum regarding Clum family history. Includes a Clum coat-of-arms. (Relation of these individuals to John Clum is unknown.). August-September, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Synopsis of the motion picture "Walk the Proud Land," based on John Clum's career as Apache Indian Agent. May 22, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Program from Tau Beta Pi Arizona Alpha Initiation Banquet. December 4, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Excerpt of letter from Marjorie Clum Parker, John Clum's granddaughter, to Phyllis Ball, University of Arizona Special Collections Librarian. May 17, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Series IX: Materials concerning Woodworth Clum
  - Autobiographical essays. No Date (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - An Epilogue to Apache Agent by Woodworth Clum. Privately published. Inscribed to Dan Carter Beard. One typescript version and one published version. 1936 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook. Most of the materials concern Woodworth Clum. 1904-1911 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Clum Travel Talks brochure. 1905 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Roster of the "Ends of the Earth" club. 1907 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Series X: Photographs
  - Subseries 1: John Clum and Family
    - John Clum, age 19, freshman at Rutgers University. 1870 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Clum, Mary Clum, and Woodworth Clum, in front of their house in Tombstone, AZ. 1880 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Clum with Ed Engelstadt and Wyatt Earp, Nome, AK. 1898 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Clum in post office, Nome AK. Circa. 1898 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Clum. 1916 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Clum, Tucson. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Clum and Walter Cole (Editor of the Tombstone Epitaph newspaper), Tombstone, AZ. 1931 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John and Mary Clum. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John and Mary Clum. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Clum with unidentified woman. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Clum with unidentified group of people. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Clum, Degleet Noor Date Garden, Imperial County, CA. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Clum, Degleet Noor Date Garden, Imperial County, CA. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Florence Baker Clum, Degleet Noor Date Garden, Imperial County, CA. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Florence Baker Clum, Degleet Noor Date Garden, Imperial County, CA. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Landscape, Degleet Noor Date Garden, Imperial County, CA. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Landscape, Degleet Noor Date Garden, Imperial County, CA. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Mary Clum. June 23, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Mary Clum (tintype and print). No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Angelina Dennison Ware (mother of Mary Clum). No Date (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Angelina Dennison Ware (mother of Mary Clum). No Date (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Angelina Dennison Ware (mother of Mary Clum). No Date (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Thomas C. Ware (father of Mary Clum). September, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Thomas C. Ware, Cynthiana, KY (grandfather of Mary Clum). No Date (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Woodworth Clum, football team photo. 1895 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Woodworth Clum (two photos glued to paper with other unidentified photos). No Date (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Woodworth Clum. No Date (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Woodworth Clum, Washington, DC. No Date (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - William Henry Clum (father of John Clum), Elizabeth Van Deusen Clum (mother of John Clum), Jane Clum (sister of John Clum), and Woodworth Clum, Washington, DC. Circa. 1888 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Photograph of a Tucson Daily Citizen newspaper clipping re: assassination attempt on John Clum. December 16, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified boy (tintype). No Date (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2: John Clum and Indians
    - John Clum with a group of unidentified Apaches from San Carlos Indian Agency, and a Yaqui boy named Juan De Quilla, Tucson. October, 1874 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - John Clum with Apaches, San Carlos Indian Agency. (standing left: Ochecama; standing right: Cha-thle-pah; sitting left: Chim-au-hua-va Sal; sitting right: Mojave Charlie; boy in photo is unidentified). 1876 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - John Clum with Apaches, Arizona. (left: Chatto/Diablo; right: Eskiminzin). 1876 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - John Clum with Apache Indian Police, including Tau-el-cly-ee and Marijildo Grijalba, Tucson. May, 1876 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - John Clum with group of unidentified Apaches, Washington, DC. September, 1876 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - John Clum with group of unidentified Apaches, San Carlos, AZ. 1931 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - John Clum with an unidentified Apache, San Carlos, AZ. 1931 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - John Clum on visit to San Carlos, AZ. 1931 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 3: Friends of John Clum
    - Virgil Earp, Tombstone, AZ. 1881 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Nellie Cashman in front of her store in Dawson, AK. Photograph by John Clum. June 23, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Captain Clay Beauford. No Date (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Dick Gird with unidentified group of people. No Date (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Ed Schieffelin. No Date (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Dick Gird, Al Schieffelin, and Ed Schieffelin. No Date (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4: Geronimo
    - Geronimo with Capt. Roberts, Nana, Lieutenant Maus, Captain Bourke, General Crook, and unidentified soldiers and Apaches. 1886 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Geronimo with Naiche at Fort Bowie, AZ. 1886 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Geronimo with Naiche at Fort Bowie, AZ. 1886 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Geronimo with Chihuahua, Naiche, Loco, and Nana, Mount Vernon Barracks, AL. 1893 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Photo of a painting of Geronimo created at Fort Sill, OK. 1898 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Geronimo in overcoat. 1904 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Geronimo with Naiche and group of Apaches in front of train. No Date (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Geronimo with rifle. No Date (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Geronimo with rifle. No Date (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Geronimo in horned headpiece. No Date (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Book: Geronimo: The Apache Chief, photos by C.S. Fly, published by Mrs. M.E. Fly, Tombstone, AZ. 1886 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 5: Apache Indians
    - Diablo, a Coyotero Apache, Washington, DC. Photo taken on trip with John Clum. 1876 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Sneezer, Washington, DC. Photo taken on trip with John Clum. October, 1876 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Eskiminzin. 1876 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Casadora and wife, Washington, DC. 1876 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Tah-Zay, son of Cochise, Chiricahua Apache, Washington, DC. Photo taken on trip with John Clum. Tah-Zay died of pneumonia in Washington, DC and is buried in Congressional Cemetery. 1876 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Victorio, Warm Springs Apache, Ojo Caliente, NM. 1877 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Eskiminzin and children. 1880 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Granddaughter of Eskiminzin with baby, San Carlos, AZ. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Sneezer and Goodah Goodah, San Carlos, AZ. 1931 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Sneezer. 1931 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Naiche on a horse. No Date (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Naiche and wife. No Date (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Tau-el-cly-ee, sergeant in Clum's Apache police force. No Date (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Detachment of Indian scouts, Ft. Huachuca, AZ. Includes Juan Antonio, Silas Tenejeheh, Abjo Quintiro, William Major, Sinew Riley, Joe Adley, Jim Lane, Jess Billy, Kessay, Andrew Paxson, Benson Sisto, Deklay, Capt. Charles Bones, Sgt. Chow Big, Eskiplygojo, Cpl. Thomas Sye, Toney James. No Date (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Deklay, Capt. Charles Bones, Sgt. Chow Big, Eskiplygojo, Cpl. Thomas Sye. No Date (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Apache women. No Date (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Apache women. (Three photos glued to sheet of scrapbook paper). No Date (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Apaches. No Date (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Apache homes. No Date (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 6: Tombstone, AZ
    - View of town. No Date (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - View of town. No Date (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - View of town. No Date (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified building. No Date (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified building. No Date (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Boot Hill Cemetery. No Date (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Mining building. No Date (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Tombstone Consolidated Mines building postcard. No Date (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 7: Alaska
    - Packers ascending the summit of Chilcoot Pass, AK. 1898 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Packers ascending the summit of Chilcoot Pass, AK. Photograph by E.A. Hegg. 1898 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Packers ascending the summit of Chilcoot Pass, AK. Photograph by E.A. Hegg. 1898 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Packers at the summit of Chilcoot Pass, AK. Photograph by E.A. Hegg. 1898 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Jeff "Soapy" Smith, Skaguay, AK. Circa. 1898 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Red Line Transportation Company's horse and cart team's last trip, Bennet, British Columbia. Photograph by M.C. Barley. July 6, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Aerial view of Dawson, Alaska from across the Yukon River. Photograph by E.A. Hegg. No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - White Horse, AK. No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Lewis Lake, AK. No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - View east of Rocky Point, AK. Photograph by H.C. Barley. No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Yukon Dock, AK. No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Broadway, Skagway, AK. Photograph taken in daylight at midnight. No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - White Pass and Yukon Railroad shops at Skagaway, AK. No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shops and coal bunkers, Skagaway, AK (?). No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Aerial view, Skagaway, AK(?). No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Aerial view, Skagaway, AK(?). No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Group of unidentified people and train, Skagaway, AK(?). No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Ships and dock, Skagaway, AK(?) No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Ships and dock, Skagaway, AK(?) No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified ship. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified ship. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified ships. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified ship. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified ship. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified ship. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified ship. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified ship. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified men in front of unidentified ship. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - White Pass and Yukon Railroad train. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - White Pass and Yukon Railroad train. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - White Pass and Yukon Railroad train track. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified train. Photograph by H.C. Barley. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified train. Photograph by H.C. Barley. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Post office, unidentified location. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified men and lumber. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified landscape. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified man with horse and dog. Photograph by H.C. Barley. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified men with mining equipment. No Date (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 8: San Bernadino, CA
    - San Bernadino County Citrus Fair in New York City. John P. Clum, Manager. 1890 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Office of Clum and O'Connor Real Estate, San Bernadino, CA. No Date (Box 5, Folder 12)